Dhanapal Jayapandi

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

11675 Rainwater Dr, Alpharetta, GA 30009

□ 678-666-0066 | 🌴 twobitjay.github.io | 🖸 twobitjay | 🛅 twobitjay | 💆 twobitjay

Summary _____

Software engineering manager, and architect with 10+ years of professional experience. Solid track record in designing and implementing elegant and pragmatic solutions for enterprise applications. History of excellence in Digital transformation, CloudOps & DevOps, Data & Analytics and Wireless technologies (5G, LTE). A growth mindset is kept by seeking new challenges and learning new skills, languages, and tools. Aim to utilize my analytical and technical expertise to impact core business strategy and results of a growing higher performance organization.

Work Experience _____

Amdocs Inc. Atlanta, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER Oct. 2011 - Present

- · Architect, design, and implement solutions for network transformation, digital transformation, data analytics, 5G, and AI projects.
- Spearheaded the development of new products and enhancements to existing products to drive the business forward.
- Hired, coached, and managed a high-performance engineering team.
- Designed and developed a comprehensive orchestration platform to manage life cycle operations of 5G and next-generation network services.

 The platform reduced the time and cost of deployments by more than 50%.
- Architected and developed a Generic VNF Manager that handles life cycle operations of a 5G network functions in a lab environment.
- Designed and developed a cloud-native business intelligence and intuitive reporting platform that allows business users to gain AI-driven insights from diverse billing data sources.
- Designed and developed RESTful microservices for bill payment and bill presentment APIs that increased the overall performance by 5x.
- Conceptualized, redesigned, and optimized ETL processor to extract invoices data from billing data feed into NoSQL datastore using Apache Spark, Hadoop and Python.
- Spearheaded development of Mass data load system, MDE, to help business with mass campaigns, adjustments, and BOGO offers for Tier 1 telecommunications company.
- Revamped sophisticated applications to reduce system coupling; directed parallelized algorithms to improve the performance by 500%.
- Promoted Agile transformation efforts to improve team velocity by 2x times instituted retrospectives, continuous integration, code reviews and automated testing.
- Administered proof of concept efforts to help with pre-sales and new technology standards.
- Partnered with other organizational leaders and customers on aligning technology vision and strategy with business direction, growth strategies, and talent strategies.

Amdocs Inc. St. Louis, USA

Development Expert Oct. 2009 - Sep. 2011

- Designed and developed an intuitive and easy-to-use Amdocs Dispute and Adjustment module for an estimated 50% efficiency gain in operations and potential savings of more than 500K per month to the customer.
- Formulated and developed a High Availability solution to keep the Amdocs Enterprise CRM application running 24x7 in production system.
- · Managed overall service infrastructure focusing on high-availability, business continuity, and system performance.
- · Identified security risks, performance issues, technical debts, and recommended changes to simplify application's on-going maintenance.
- Mentored junior software developers helping with knowledge on best practices, and CRM implementation.
- · Promoted to Software engineering manager within 24 months due to solid performance and organizational impact.

Amdocs Development Ltd Limassol, Cyprus

SENIOR SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

July. 2006 - Oct. 2009

- · Analyzed new features from customers and proposed technology solutions to implement on top of the existing Amdocs platform.
- Developed and maintained Amdocs CRM application for several T1 service providers.
- Implemented Amdocs CRM v7.5 for a Tier1 company to manage e-service tickets.
- Authored proof-of-concept to show the business value of Amdocs CRM to DishNET, Telstra, and Excelcom.
- · Provided bug fixes, fixed performance issues, optimized queries, and improved Amdocs CRM and OMS product usability.
- · Providing Technical guidance and explaining advanced concepts of Amdocs CRM product to other members in the work area.

Amdocs Development Ltd

Limassol, Cyprus

SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

Oct. 2004 - Jun. 2006

- Designed, developed, and deployed large-scale CRM for Deutsche Telekom and Vodafone UK.
- Implemented a logging framework for Deutsche Telekom to log messages in Eclipse Common Base Event (CBE) format.
- Analyzed and fixed performance issues and functional defects in the Amdocs CRM product.
- Provided bug fixes for Amdocs eCare Integration APIs.
- Involved in the certification of Orion and Omega release of Amdocs CRM.

Key Skills _____

LanguagesJava, J2EE, JavaScript, Typescript, Python, GO, PHP, Perl, Unix Shells, AWKBackendSpring framework, SpringBoot, Node.js, Express, Django, Flask, Laravel

Frontend Angular, React.js, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass

Databases Oracle, MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, Redis

Cloud & Containers AWS, Azure, Openstack, Openshift, Kubernetes, Helm, Traefik, Rancher

CI/CD/Tools Docker, Ansible, Git, Nexus, Jenkins, Gradle, Maven, Nagios, Vagrant

Data & Analytics Tableau, Sisense Periscope, Hadoop, Spark, Elastic, Snowflake

Systems Red Hat Linux 5/6/7/8, Sun Solaris, IBM AIX, Ubuntu, Weblogic, JBOSS, Apache Tomcat EE, Nginx

Others Technical leadership, Software architecture, Emerging technologies

Certifications

2020 AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate, AWS

2020 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, AWS

2019 **SAFe Agilist**, Scaled Agile Framework

2013 Project Management Professional (PMP), PMI

2008 Sun Certified Java Developer, J2SE 5.0

2006 Sun Certified Web Component Developer, J2EE 1.4

2005 Sun Certified Java Programmer, J2SE 5.0

Education

College of Engineering, Guindy (Anna University)

Guindy, India

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Jun. 1999 - May. 2003

• Received Gupta Scholarship, 1999 - 2003, for academic excellence in the computer science department.